Guide to the Lincoln Steffens Papers
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Lincoln Steffens Papers
1863-1936.
Steffens, Lincoln, 1866-1936.
ca. 37,186 items (78 boxes, 1 flat box, 1 bundle)
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library, New York, NY.
4079365
Lincoln Steffens (1866-1936) was an American journalist - a leading writer among the "muckrakers" of early 20th century - as well as a lecturer, political philosopher, and reformer. The collection contains correspondence, clippings, diaries, manuscripts, photographs, and other materials.
History
Lincoln Steffens (1866-1936) was an American journalist - a leading writer among the "muckrakers" of early 20th century - as well as a lecturer, political philosopher, and reformer.
Steffens, the son of a wealthy businessman, was born in San Francisco, and grew up primarily in Sacramento, California. He graduated from the University of California at Berkeley in 1889, and continued his studies in Europe afterwards.
Upon retuning to the United States in 1892, Steffens began working in the newspaper industry in New York City. in 1903, he became editor of McClure's Magazine, where he published a series of articles on corruption in American cities, later published as as a collection in the The Shame of Cities in 1904. This was followed by an investigation into state politicians in The Struggle for Self-Government in 1906.
Steffens continued in journalism until approximately 1910, when he became interested in the revolution in Mexico. He traveled to Mexico to report on the revolution, and later also traveled to Russia shortly after its revolution. In the 1920s, he moved to Europe, and began working on his autobiography, which was highly successful upon its publication in 1931.
Steffens died in Carmel, California, in 1936.
Scope and Content
The collection contains correspondence, manuscripts, documents, photographs, clippings, diaries, date books, address books, and printed material of Steffens.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into four series by accession.
Subjects
Winter, Ella, 1898-1980.; Steffens, Josephine Bontecou.; Lindsey, Ben B. (Ben Barr), 1869-1943.; Darrow, Clarence, 1857-1938.; Davidson, Jo, 1883-1952.; Jeffers, Robinson, 1887-1962.; Goldman, Emma, 1869-1940.; Pound, Ezra, 1885-1972.; Roosevelt, Theodore, 1887-1944.; Sinclair, Upton, 1878-1968.; United States--Politics and government.; Literature.; Journalism.; Photoprints.; Diaries.; Journalists.
Access Restrictions
This collection has no restrictions.
The manuscript materials are located on-site.
Acquisition
1950, 1966, 1978. Purchase from Ella Winter.
Alternate Formats
Microfilm is available for parts of collection; see the container list for more detailed information.
Finding aid in repository.
- Series I
  The original collection (Series I) contains letters to Steffens and Ella Winter from friends, family, and associates in political, literary, and journalistic fields; edited typescript copies of Steffens' outgoing correspondence, used in the publication of THE LETTERS OF LINCOLN STEFFENS; and manuscripts of many of Steffens' articles and essays (all of the preceding are available on microfilm). Also, newspaper clippings about and by Steffens; files of periodicals such as THE CARMELITE to which Steffens contributed, manuscripts of Josephine Bontecou Steffens, first wife of Lincoln Steffens, and a small group of letters from Ben B. Lindsay and Lincoln Steffens. Additional Steffens material includes cataloged and uncataloged letters to Steffens and Ella Winter; duplicate copies of Steffens' edited letters; manuscripts of articles, essays, and book drafts by Steffens and others; diaries, datebooks, and address books of Steffens and others; miscellaneous manuscripts and documents relating to Steffens; photographs, including several by Edward Weston; miscellaneous printed material; and original outgoing letters of Steffens, 1888-1936. Correspondents include Clarence Darrow, Jo Davidson, Robinson Jeffers, Emma Goldman, Ezra Pound, Theodore Roosevelt, and Upton Sinclair.
  - Subseries I.1. Correspondence--A-Z
    Includes copies of Steffens’ outgoing letters, arranged alphabetically by recipient.
    Also available on microfilm, Series I. Reels 1-6
    - A-B (Box 1)
    - C (Box 2)
    - D-E (Box 3)
    - F (Box 4)
    - G-He (Box 5)
    - Hi-I (Box 6)
    - J-K (Box 7)
    - L (Box 8)
    - M-N (Box 9)
    - O-P (Box 10)
    - R-Sk (Box 11)
    - Sl-Steffens, Lincoln--A-E (Box 12)
    - Steffens, Lincoln
      - F-St (Box 13)
      - Su-Willis (Box 14)
      - Winter-Z (Box 15)
    - Steffens-V (Box 15)
    - W-Z (Box 16)
  - Subseries I.2. Additions to Correspondence, received 1966
    (Not on Microfilm)
    - Lindsey, Ben B. to E.A. Filene, undated, (a.l.s. 4p) (Box 17)
    - Steffens, Lincoln
      - To ?, 1908 February 1, (a.l.s., lp) (Box 17)
      - To Luis Bossero, 1961 May 24, (a.l.s., 2p.) (Box 17)
      - To Mr. Phenix, 1920 November 3, (a.l.s. 2p.) (Box 17)
      - To E.A. Filene, 1927 April 6, (a.l.s. 2p.) (Box 17)
      - To Mr. Procter, 1932 September 26., (a.l.s. lp) (Box 17)
      - To Lillian Schoedler, 1936 June 18, (t.l.s., lp.) (Box 17)
  - Subseries I.3. Manuscripts, 1889-1936
    (Also available on microfilm, Series I, Reels 7-10)
    - 1889-1990 (Box 18)
    - 1901-1906 (Box 19)
    - 1907-1910 (Box 21)
    - 1911-1936 (Box 20)
  - Subseries I.4. Typescripts--A-Z
    Correspondence copies
    Not available on microfilm.
    - A-H (Box 22)
    - I-Y (Box 23)
    - Steffens (Box 24)
    - Suggett
      - Allen, Lou, and family (Box 25)
      - Laura (Box 26-27)
    - Winter (Box 28)
  - Subseries I.5. Manuscripts of Josephine Bontecou Steffens
    (Not available on microfilm)
    - General (Box 29)
    - The Deans
      - Chapters 1-20 (Box 30)
      - Chapters 21-35 (Box 31)
  - Subseries I.6. Scrapbooks
    (These are also available on microfilm, Series I, Reel 11.)
    - Scrapbooks I & III (Box 32)
    - Oversized Scrapbooks (Box 2 Items)
  - Subseries I.7. Clippings
    - Autobiography Reviews (Box 33)
    - California (Box 34)
    - Chicago-Denver (Box 35)
    - Greenwich-Massachusetts (Box 36)
    - Mexico-New Jersey (Box 37)
    - R (Box 38)
    - Steffens (Box 39)
    - Socialism-Wall Street (Box 40)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 41-43)
    - USSR (Box 44)
    - Chronological (Dated), 1903-1908 (Box 45)
  - Subseries I.8. The Carmelite
    - The Carmelite (Box 46-47)
  - Subseries I.9. Pacific Weekly
    - Pacific Weekly (Box 50)
  - Subseries I.10. Miscellaneous
    - List of Steffens’ Articles (Box 48)
    - List of Letters Sold (Box 48)
    - Envelopes (Box 48)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 49)
  - Subseries I.11. Printed Materials
    - Mrs. Steffen’s Scrapbook (Box 51)
- Series II.
  Series II, added in 1978, contains catalogued and uncatalogued letters to Steffens and Ella Winter; duplicate copies of Steffens' edited letters; manuscripts of articles, essays and book drafts by Steffens and others; diaries, datebooks and address books of Steffens and others; miscellaneous manuscripts and documents relatidg to Steffens; photographs, including several by Edward Weston; and miscellaneous printed material. Among the many prominent correspondents are Clarence Darrow, Jo Davidson, Robinson Jeffers, Emma Goldman, Ezra Pound, Theodore Roosevelt and Upton Sinclair.
  - Subseries II.1. Cataloged Correspondence
    (Also available on microfilm, Series II, Reel 1.)
    - Austin, Mary Hunter (Box 52)
    - Barnett, Joseph (Box 52)
    - Barry, John Daniel (Box 52)
    - Bird, William (Box 52)
    - Bliven, Bruce (Box 52)
    - Boni, Albert (Box 52)
    - Bontecou, Susan (Box 52)
    - Bourke-White, Margaret (Box 52)
    - Briggs, George A. (Box 52)
    - Brooks, John Graham (Box 52)
    - Burrows, Peggy Palmer (Box 52)
    - Cagney, James (Box 52)
    - Canby, Henry Seidel (Box 52)
    - Cantwell, Betsy (Mrs. Robert) (Box 52)
    - Cantwell, Robert (Box 52)
    - Clarke, Joseph Ignatius Constantine (Box 52)
    - Constantine, Arthur (Box 52)
    - Coons, Alvin (Box 52)
    - Cowley, Malcolm (Box 52)
    - Creel, George (Box 52)
    - Darcy, Samuel Adams (Box 52)
    - Darrow, Clarence (Box 52)
    - Darrow, Ruby (Mrs. Clarence) (Box 52)
    - Davidson, Jo (Box 52)
    - Davidson, Yvonne (Mrs. Jo) (Box 52)
    - Debs, Eugene V. (Box 52)
    - Dreiser, Theodore (Box 52)
    - Field, Sara Bard (Box 52)
    - Filene, Edward Albert (Box 52)
    - Fisher, H. H. (Box 52)
    - Flavin, Martin (Box 52)
    - Force, James G. (Box 52)
    - Foster, William Z (Box 52)
    - Frank, [Glenn] (Box 52)
    - Frederick, J. George (Box 52)
    - Freeman, Joseph (Box 52)
    - Garland, Hamlin (Box 52)
    - Garret, Garet (Box 52)
    - Goldman, Emma (Box 52)
    - Goldschmidt, Hans (Box 52)
    - Hale, John E. (Box 52)
    - Hall, Bolton (Box 52)
    - Hall, Gilman (Box 52)
    - Hapgood, Hutchins (Box 52)
    - Hapgood, Norman (Box 52)
    - Harcourt, Alfred (Box 52)
    - Hart, Henry (Box 52)
    - Havel, Hippolyte (Box 52)
    - Hawthorne, Julian (Box 52)
    - Hickok, Guy (Box 52)
    - Hicks, Granville (Box 52)
    - Hollis, Henry French (Box 52)
    - Hollister, Dot Steffens (Mrs. John James) (Box 52)
    - Hollister, Jane B. (Box 52)
    - Hopper, James (Box 52)
    - Howe, Frederic Clemson (Box 52)
    - Huebsch, Ben W (Box 52)
    - Jeffers, Robinson (Box 52)
    - Jeffers, Una (Box 52)
    - Kallen, Horace Meyer (Box 52)
    - Kawakami, K.K. (Box 52)
    - Kellogg, Paul U. (Box 52)
    - Kennerley, Mitchell (Box 52)
    - Keogh, Andrew (Box 52)
    - Knopf, Alfred A (Box 52)
    - Knox, Frank (Box 52)
    - Krudewolf, Johann Friedrich (Box 52)
    - La Follette, Fola (Box 52)
    - Leonov, Leonid Maksimovich (Box 52)
    - Lewis, Fay (Box 52)
    - Lindsay, Ben B (Box 52)
    - Liveright, Horace (Box 52)
    - McClure, Samuel Sidney (Box 52)
    - McNamara, J.B. (Box 52)
    - Marland, Ernest Whitworth (Box 52)
    - Martin, John (Box 52)
    - Mencken, Henry Louis (Box 52)
    - Minor, Robert (Box 52)
    - Mooney, Tom (Box 52)
    - Nobbes, Etta B. ("Gussie") (Box 53)
    - Older, Fremont (Box 53)
    - Perkins, Frances (Box 53)
    - Pettigrew, Richard Franklin (Box 53)
    - Polk, Frank Lyon (Box 53)
    - Pound, Ezra Loomis (Box 53)
    - Reed, John (Box 53)
    - Rolph, James, Jr. (Box 53)
    - Roosevelt, Franklin Delano (Box 53)
    - Roosevelt, Theodore (Box 53)
    - Sandburg, Carl (Box 53)
    - Schroeder, Theodore (Box 53)
    - Shepard, Elliott F. (Box 53)
    - Sholokhov, Mikhail Aleksandrovich (Box 53)
    - Sinclair, Upton (Box 53)
    - Smith, Harrison (Box 53)
    - Steffens, Joseph (Box 53)
    - Steffens, Lincoln (Box 53)
    - Stein, Leo (Box 53)
    - Stone, Harlan Fiske (Box 53)
    - Strong, Anna Louise (Box 53)
    - Suggett, Allen H. (Box 53)
    - Suggett, Laura Steffens (second Mrs. Allen H.} (Box 53)
    - Van Loon, Kendrik Willem (Box 53)
    - Walsh, Richard J. (Box 53)
    - Wheeler, John N (Box 53)
    - Winter, Ella (Box 53)
    - Wood, Charles Erskine Scott (Box 53)
    - Wyzanski, Charles E., Jr. (Box 53)
    - Young, Art (Box 53)
    - Young, Owen D. (Box 53)
  - Subseries II.2. Uncataloged Correspondence
    - Letters to Steffens, A-Z (Box 54)
      (These are also available on the following microfilm reels - Series II--Correspondence, Reel 1 (A-G) and Reel 2 (H-Z) )
    - Letters by Steffens, 1889-1936
      (Edited typescript copies)
      - 1889-1915 (Box 55)
      - 1916-1924 (Box 56)
      - 1925-1936 (Box 57)
      - Hemingway, Ernest (To) (Box 57)
      - Hollister, Jane B. (To) (Box 57)
    - Correspondence of Werner Brandes about Lincoln Steffens, (Photocopies) (Box 54)
  - Subseries II.3. Manuscripts, Documents, and Photographs--Cataloged
    (Also available on microfilm; Series II. Manuscripts, Documents, and Photographs, Reel 1, except for "Notes for Ethics.")
    - A-R
      - Bontecou, Susan (Box 58)
      - Cantwell, Robert (Box 58)
      - Davidson, Jo (Box 58)
      - Dos Passos, John (Box 58)
      - Francis, David R. (Box 58)
      - Jeffers, Robinson (Box 58)
      - Morley, Christopher (Box 58)
      - Phillips, John S. (Box 58)
    - S-End
      - Steffens, Joseph (Box 59)
      - Steffens, Josephine Bontecou (first Mrs. Lincoln) (Box 59)
      - Steffens, Lincoln (Box 59)
      - Stone, Harlan Fiske (Box 59)
      - Throckmorton, Cleon (Box 59)
      - Weston, Edward (Box 59)
      - Winter, Ella (Box 59)
      - Wood, Charles Erskine Scott (Box 59)
  - Subseries II.4. Manuscripts--Uncataloged
    (Also available on microfilm; Series II. Manuscripts, Documents, and Photographs, Reels 1-2)
    - Steffens, Lincoln (Box 59)
      - Student Comments on a Speech by Steffens. (Box 59)
      - Autobiography--Items About (Box 59)
      - Manuscripts and items about Steffens, by Ella Winter and others (Box 59)
      - Writings--Miscellaneous manuscripts and documents about. (Box 59)
    - Manuscripts and Notes--Miscellaneous and Unidentified (Box 59)
    - Mimeographed Material--Miscellaneous (Box 59)
  - Subseries II.5. Diaries, Books, and Date Books, (28 volumes)
    (Also available on microfilm; Series II. Manuscripts, Documents, and Photographs, Reels 2-3)
    - Bontecou, Susan. Diary, 1911, (1 volume) (Box 60)
    - Steffens, Josephine Bontecou (first Mrs. Lincoln)
      - Diaries, 1883-1899, (11 volumes) (Box 60)
      - Address Books, (2 volumes) (Box 60)
    - Steffens, Lincoln
      - Diary, 1906, (1 volume) (Box 60)
      - Address Books, 1905 and Undated, (8 volumes) (Box 60)
      - Date Books, 1919-1931, (8 volumes) (Box 60)
    - Subseries II.6. Documents and Miscellaneous Items--Uncataloged (Box 60)
      (Also available on microfilm; Series II. Manuscripts, Documents, and Photographs, Reel 3)
    - Documents
      - 1863-1894--Regarding Krudewolf Estate and Family. (Box 61)
      - 1894--Regarding Krudewolf Estate and Family--Correspondence with W. Lorenz. (Box 61)
      - 1890-1891--German, Miscellaneous (Box 61)
      - 1905-1906--Deeds, Titles, etc. (Connecticut property) (Box 61)
      - 1917-1920--Russian (Box 61)
      - Insurance (Box 61)
      - Passports and Visas (Box 61)
      - Steffens, Josephine Bontecou (first Mrs. Lincoln) (Box 61)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 61)
    - Calling Card (Box 61)
    - Memorabilia (Box 61)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 61)
  - Subseries II.7. Photographs
    (Also available on microfilm; Series II. Manuscripts, Documents, and Photographs, Reel 4)
    - Lincoln Steffens--Miscellaneous (Box 62)
    - Lincoln and Pete Steffens (some with Ella Winter and others) (Box 62)
    - Lincoln Steffens, Sara Bard Field, C.E.S. Wood - Los Gatos, California (Box 62)
    - Pete Steffens
      - (Childhood) - miscellaneous o. (Box 62)
      - (Adulthood) - miscellaneous (Box 62)
    - Pete Steffens and Ella Winter (Box 62)
    - Ella Winter (Box 62)
    - Jo Davidson (Box 62)
    - Miscellaneous Persons and Places (Box 62)
  - Subseries II.8. Printed Materials
    - Clippings, (2 Folders) (Box 63)
    - Steffens, Lincoln--Writings. Printed copies. (Box 63)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 63)
- Series III. Letters of Lincoln Steffens
  Series III consists of the original outgoing letters of Lincoln Steffens,1888- 1936, along with several miscellaneous letters and related items. (12 boxes, 1686 pieces).
  (These are also available on microfilm; Series III - Reel 1: 1886?-May 17, 1912; Reel 2: May 24, 1912-August 2, 1920; Reel 3: August 5, 1920-1927; Reel 4: 1928-end)
  - Bjorkman, Edwin. To Arthur Collitscher, 1922 April 22, (a.l.s., 1p.) (Box 64)
  - Bolton, A.G. (?). To Lincoln Steffens, 1914 March 17, (a.c.p.s., 1p.) (Box 64)
  - Cabot, Higginson. To Lincoln Steffens, 1914 May 13, (a.l.s., 2p.) (Box 64)
  - Field, Sara Bard and C.E.S. Wood. To Lincoln Steffens and Ella Winter, 1924 July 30, (a.l.s., 1p.) (Box 64)
    (Signed with initials of S.H.)
  - Steffens, Lincoln. To Ella Winter, 1924 August 1, (a.l.s., 1p. On verso of above letter) (Box 64)
  - Hapgood, Norman. To Lincoln Steffens, 1922 March 15, (t.l.s., 1p.) (Box 64)
    (With related letter)
  - Hollister, Dot Steffens
    - To Ella Winter and Lincoln Steffens, 1928 January 26, (a.l.s., 8p.) (Box 64)
    - To Lincoln Steffens, 1928 February 18, (a.l.s., 10p.) (Box 64)
  - Hollister, Jane. To Lincoln Steffens, 1927 March, (a.l.s., 3p.) (Box 64)
  - Lisher, [Benno Edward]. To Allen H. Suggett, 1916 October 30, (a.l.s., 1p.) (Box 64)
    (On card)
  - Nobbes, Etta B. (Gussie). To DOT STEFFENS HOLLISTER (MRS. JOHN JAMES), 1912 June 22, (a.l.s., 4p.) (Box 64)
  - Post, Louis Freeland. To Lincoln Steffens, 1918 September 18, (a.l.s., 1p.) (Box 64)
    (With note in hand of Lincoln Steffens to Laura Steffens Suggett (2nd Mrs. Allen H.) and Allen H. Suggett)
  - Roberts, John W. To Lincoln Steffens, circa 1916 July 20, (a.l.s., 4p.) (Box 64)
  - Shaw, Carleton A. To Lincoln Steffens, 1917 January 5, (a.l.s., 2p.) (Box 64)
  - Shaw, G. Howland. To Lincoln Steffens, 1920 December 3, (t.l.s., 2p.) (Box 64)
  - Steffens, Joseph. To "Cousin Mary", 1899 February 1, (t.l. (copy), 2p.) (Box 64)
  - Steffens, Josephine
    - To Elizabeth Louise Symes Steffens, 1898 May 8, (t.l.s., 2p., with envelope) (Box 64)
    - To Joseph Steffens, 1907 March 19, (t.l.s., 1p.) (Box 64)
  - Steffens, Lincoln
    - To Elizabeth Louise Symes Steffens, 1888 May 8, (a.l.s., 2p.) (Box 64)
    - To Elizabeth Louise Symes Steffens, circa 1889, (a.l.s., 2p.) (Box 64)
      (Signed with initials, faded and damaged)
    - To Elizabeth Louise Symes Steffens, 1889 July 21, (a.l.s., 3p., with envelope) (Box 64)
    - To Elizabeth Louise Symes Steffens, 1889 August 3, (a.l.s., 4p.) (Box 64)
    - To Lou Steffens Suggett (1st Mrs. Allen H.), 1889 August 3, (a.l.s., 8p.) (Box 64)
    - To Laura Steffens Suggett (2nd Mrs. Allen H.), 1889 August 18, (a.l.s., 8p.) (Box 64)
    - To Lou Steffens Suggett (1st Mrs. Allen H.), 1889 August 25, (a.l.s., 10p.) (Box 64)
    - To Joseph Steffens, 1889 September 23-25, (a.l.s., 4p., with envelope) (Box 64)
    - To Laura Steffens Suggett (2nd Mrs. Allen H.), 1889 October 2, (a.l.s., 4p.) (Box 64)
    - To Dot Steffens Hollister (Mrs. John James), 1889 October 25, (a.l.s., 4p.) (Box 64)
    - To Lou Steffens Suggett (1st Mrs. Allen H.), 1889 November, (a.l.s., 4p.) (Box 64)
    - To Joseph Steffens, 1889 November 1, (a.l.s., 4p., with envelope) (Box 64)
    - To Dot Steffens Hollister (Mrs. John James), 1889 November 10, (a.l.s., 4p.) (Box 64)
    - To Lou Steffens Suggett (1st Mrs. Allen H.), 1889 November 16, (a.l.s., 4p.) (Box 64)
    - To Elizabeth Louise Symes Steffens, 1889 November 30, (a.l.s., 4p.) (Box 64)
    - To Elizabeth Louise Symes Steffens, 1889 December 7, (a.l.s., 2p.) (Box 64)
    - To Elizabeth Louise Symes Steffens, 1889 December 15, (a.l.s., 6p.) (Box 64)
    - To Lou Steffens Suggett (1st Mrs. Allen H.), 1890 January 19, (a.l.s., 2p.) (Box 64)
    - To Lou Steffens Suggett (1st Mrs. Allen H.), 1890 February 3, (a.l.s., 1p.) (Box 64)
    - To Dot Steffens Hollister (Mrs. John James), 1890 February 3, (a.l.) (Box 64)
      (Enclosed with the above letter)
    - To Elizabeth Louise Symes Steffens, 1890 February 15, (a.l.s., 4p.) (Box 64)
    - To Frederick Milton Willis, 1890 April 19, (a.l.s., 2p.) (Box 64)
    - To Frederick Milton Willis?, 1890 April 12, (a.l.s., 6p.) (Box 64)
    - To Joseph Steffens, 1890 May 3, (a.l.s., 4p.) (Box 64)
    - To Dot Steffens Hollister (Mrs. John James), 1890 May 4, (a.l.s., 2p.) (Box 64)
    - To Elizabeth Louise Symes Steffens, 1890 May 16, (a.l.s., 4p.) (Box 64)
    - To Joseph Steffens, 1890 May 19, (a.l.s., 2p.) (Box 64)
    - To Joseph Steffens, 1890 May 28, (a.l.s., 6p., with envelope) (Box 64)
    - To Joseph Steffens, 1890 July 18, (a.l.s., 2p.) (Box 64)
    - To Joseph Steffens, 1890 November 11, (a.l.s., 4p., with envelope) (Box 64)
    - To Joseph Steffens, 1890 November 23, (a.l.s., 4p.) (Box 64)
    - To Joseph Steffens, 1891 June 19, (a.l.s., 4p.) (Box 64)
      (Signature cut out)
    - To Joseph Steffens, 1892 October 21, (a.l.s., 4p.) (Box 64)
    - To Joseph Steffens, 1893, (a.l.s., 8p., with envelope) (Box 64)
    - To Joseph Steffens, 1893 January 18, (a.l.s., 6p., with envelope) (Box 64)
    - To Joseph Steffens, 1893 January 26, (a.l.s., 2p., with envelope) (Box 64)
    - To Joseph Steffens, 1893 January, (a.l.s., 4p., with envelope) (Box 64)
    - To Joseph Steffens, 1893 March 3, (a.l.s., 8p., with envelope) (Box 64)
    - To Joseph Steffens, 1893 March 18, (a.l.s., 4p., with envelope) (Box 64)
    - To Johana Krudewolf, 1893 March 19, (a.l.s., 8p.) (Box 64)
    - To Joseph Steffens, 1893 July 6, (a.l.s., 4p., with envelope) (Box 64)
    - To Joseph Steffens, 1893 August 13, (a.l.s., 5p., with envelope) (Box 64)
    - To Joseph Steffens, 1893 October 22, (a.l.s., 6p., with envelope) (Box 64)
    - To Joseph Steffens, 1893 November 3, (a.l.s., 4p., with envelope) (Box 64)
    - To Joseph Steffens, 1893 November 19, (a.l.s., 4p., with envelope) (Box 64)
    - To Joseph Steffens, 1893 November 24, (a.l.s., 6p., with envelope) (Box 64)
    - To Joseph Steffens, 1894 March 11, (a.l.s., 3p., with envelope) (Box 64)
    - To Joseph Steffens, 1894 April 15, (a.l.s., 4p., with envelope) (Box 64)
    - To Joseph Steffens, 1894 May 24, (a.l.s., 4p., with envelope) (Box 64)
    - To Joseph Steffens, 1894 June 2, (a.l.s., 4p., with envelope) (Box 64)
    - To Elizabeth Louise Symes Steffens, 1894 June 26, (a.l.s., 3p., with envelope) (Box 64)
    - To Joseph Steffens, 1894 July 12, (a.l.s., 5p., with envelope) (Box 64)
    - To Joseph Steffens, 1894 July 19, (a.l.s., 3p., with envelope) (Box 64)
    - To Joseph Steffens, 1894 August 10, (a.l.s., 4p., with envelope) (Box 64)
    - To Joseph Steffens, 1894 August 16, (a.l.s., 6p., with envelope) (Box 64)
    - To Joseph Steffens, 1894 August 28, (a.l.s., 2p., with envelope) (Box 64)
    - To Joseph Steffens, 1894 October 14, (a.l.s., 3p., with envelope) (Box 64)
    - To Joseph Steffens, 1894 October 18, (a.l.s., 4p.) (Box 64)
    - To Joseph Steffens, 1894 November 4, (a.l.s., 4p.) (Box 64)
    - To Joseph Steffens, 1894 November 8, (a.l.s., 4p., with envelope) (Box 64)
    - To Joseph Steffens, circa 1894 November 27, (a.l.s., 3p.) (Box 64)
    - To Joseph Steffens, 1894 December 7, (a.l.s., 6p., with envelope) (Box 64)
    - To Joseph Steffens, 1984 December 15, (a.l.s., 4p.) (Box 64)
    - To Joseph Steffens, 1895 January 5, (a.l.s., 4p.) (Box 64)
    - To Joseph Steffens, 1895 February 16, (a.l.s., 4p.) (Box 64)
    - To Joseph Steffens, 1895 April 14, (t.l.s., 2p.) (Box 64)
    - To Elizabeth Louise Symes Steffens, 1895 May 5, (t.l.s., 3p.) (Box 64)
    - To Joseph Steffens, 1895 May 7, (a.l.s., 2p.) (Box 64)
    - To Joseph Steffens, 1895 June 9, (t.l.s., 2p., with envelope) (Box 64)
    - To Joseph Steffens, 1895 July 11, (a.l.s., 4p.) (Box 64)
    - To Joseph Steffens, 1895 September 8, (a.l.s., 4p.) (Box 64)
    - To Elizabeth Louise Symes Steffens, 1895 October 26, (t.l.s., 2p., with envelope) (Box 64)
    - To Joseph Steffens, 1895 December 15, (a.l.s., 3p.) (Box 64)
    - To Joseph Steffens, 1896 January 16, (a.l.s., 4p., with envelope) (Box 64)
    - To Joseph Steffens, circa 1896 February 2, (a.l.s., 2p., with envelope) (Box 64)
    - To Joseph Steffens, 1896 February 7, (a.l.s., 3p.) (Box 64)
    - To Joseph Steffens, 1896 February 28, (a.l.s., 3p.) (Box 64)
    - To Joseph Steffens, 1896 March 13, (a.l.s., 4p.) (Box 64)
    - To Joseph Steffens, 1896 March 20, (a.l.s., 4p.) (Box 64)
    - To Joseph Steffens, 1896 April 9, (a.l.s., 2p., with envelope) (Box 64)
    - To Joseph Steffens, 1896 April 11, (a.l.s., 2p., with envelope) (Box 64)
    - To Joseph Steffens, 1896 July 10, (t.l.s., 3p.) (Box 64)
    - To Joseph Steffens, 1896 July 12, (a.l.s., 4p., with envelope) (Box 64)
    - To Joseph Steffens, 1896 August 5, (a.l.s., 2p.) (Box 64)
    - To Joseph Steffens, 1896 August 14, (a.l.s., 2p., with envelope) (Box 64)